Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection [dates] PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 18xx-20xx
  - Subseries IX.A. Chronological, 18xx-20xx
    - Invitation to Visit The Tent (on the grounds of St. John the Divine Cathedral), undated (Folder 09-02)
      The Tent was open every night except Saturday for singing. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child/39".
    - Sunday afternoon free concert series held at the Holyrood Church, undated (Folder 09-02)
      Silk screen print by School of Industrial Art. Holyrood Church is at the corner of 179 St. & Fort Washington Ave.
    - "Jubilate! The Glorious Fourth is now doubly glorious It sees the downfall of Militarism - So Rejoice: Jubilate!", [1919?] (Folder 09-04)
      Poster features an eagle image overlaid on a red, white, blue outline of the United States. At bottom, in corner, "C-29-C"
    - "Universite de Dijon, Cours de Francais" Advertisement [French], undated (Folder 09-04)
      Poster printed by Jobard. Dijon. Poster advertises french classes -- language, literature and history -- for foreign students for a summer or a full year.
    - 1950 Annual Campaign of the Greater New York Fund (Folder 09-06)
      Poster includes an alphabetized list of voluntary services helped by the campaign. On back, a printed request to post and a stamped date: Jun 26 1950.
    - "New Life for Youth" City-Wide Youth Rally advertisement, 1951 (Folder 09-06)
      Rally sponsored by the New Life Advance Committee of New York Presbytery and featured Jackie Robinson, Chuck Templeton, and Dr. John A. MacKay. It was held at Rutgers Presbyterian Church.
    - Advertisement for The State Insurance Fund Accident Reduction Contest, 1951 (Folder 09-06)
      Reason for contest: "National Security Demands Accident Prevention" Images of workers, the globe and New York State. Stamped on back: Feb 19 1951.
    - "Join Payroll Savings" Official U.S. Treasury Poster, 1951 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Features baseball player, Ralph Kiner. Date stamped on back: Nov 7 1951.
    - "Join Payroll Savings" Official U.S. Treasury Poster, 1951 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Features a solider with the slogan, "Defense is your job too!", and a $100 Series E U.S. Bond. Stamped date on back: Sep 28 1951.
    - The 1951 New York Antiques Fair advertisement (Folder 09-06)
      Poster printed bby T.J. Lyons Press. The Fair featured exhibits by members of the Art and Antique Dealers League of America. On back, stamped "Please Post" and "Nov 7 1951".
    - New York State Insurance Fund Christmas and New Year's Greeting, 1951 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster sponsored by The State Insurance Fund of the State of New York. Stamped on back: Feb 6 1952.
    - Buy Israel Bonds. Birthday Salute to the State of Israel., 1953 (Folder 09-02)
      The event which included appearances by many actors, musicians, and Israel and American leaders, including Senators Humphrey and Morse, was held at the RKO Fordham theater.
    - "be careful...Driving...Or On Foot avoid winter accidents", 1953 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster sponsored by Group Insurance Department, The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States. Acquisition date (?) on back: January 15, 1953.
    - The 1955 New York Antiques Fair advertisement (Folder 09-06)
      The Fair was at the 71st Infantry Armory under Nuttall-Hazen Management. "Please Post" stamped on back.
    - Army Recruiting Office advertisement to "Enlist"., undated (Folder 09-05)
      2 copies. Poster printed by Byan & Hart Co. Printers, Chicago. Poster features an appeal for soliders by George Washington.
    - "For your safety, while New York sleeps, our men check your trains", 1956 (Folder 09-06)
      The New York City Transit Authority's The Subway Sun, Vol. 23, No. 13. On back, in pencil, "Oct-Nov. 1956. 207th Street Train Yards."
    - "Shop Now, Mail Early, Use Christmas Seals on all your Letters and Packages", 1957 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster printed by Malgamated Lithographers of America. Postmaster's important holiday reminders. Christmas Seals to fight Tuberculosis.
    - "National Foreign Language Week" advertisement, 1958 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster designed by Bruce Russell. Language Week sponsored by Alpha Nu Gamma National Foreign Language Society. Stamped on back: Jan 2 1976.
    - Notice of the International Longshoremen's Association Portwide Meeting, 1958 (Folder 09-06)
      Meeting to discuss "Automation in the Longshore Industry and What it Means to You". Open to Longshoremen, checkers, and allied crafts. "Attend and protect your job, your pension, your welfae benefits. At Madison Square Garden at 50th St. & 8th Ave. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Michael Staats - 1996".
    - Advertisement for Free Family Fallout Shelter Booklet from the Office of Civil and Defense Mobilization, 1959 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster printed by U.S. Government Printing Office and designed by Lee.
    - "Step up to the JobCorps. Men & Women - Age 16 to 21", ca 1965 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster features the ladder and up arrow logo. "Work, Learn, Earn away from home"
    - "Mollify them...quote Newsweek" advertisement, ca 1970 (Folder 09-06)
      Poster features a photograph of a female model with a gun next to a vintage Rolls Royce and the slogan, "the newsweekly that separates fact from opinion".
    - "City of New York Police Department Police Academy Combat Target", 1962 (Folder 09-06)
      Target used at New York Police Academy.
    - "Virginia Slims Women's Tennis Circuit", 1972 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster for a tournament held at the Newport Casino, Newport, R.I. for the benefit of the National Lawn Tennis Hall of Fame. Gift of Harley Spiller, 2022.
    - Tarrytown Fire Dept. Annual Bazaar, 1975 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster printed by Triangle Poster Co. Midway by B&B Ride Company. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: Aug 5 1975.
    - "WANTED by the New York City Police Department HORSES...", 1976 (Folder 09-07)
      The poster was designed by Sgt. Michael Daly and printed by the City of New York Police Department. The police department was looking for donated horses for the mounted police, and, according to a note on the back, H.Ross Perot donated 20 horses. The note continues that the poster was "acquired for the Exhibition "New York on the Brink" Courtesy of Nick Muglia.
    - The Great New York State Children's Party, 1979 (Folder 09-07)
      Related Materials
      Poster designed by Doug Lapp. The Children's Party was held at Battery Park in New York City and sponsored by the Governor's (Hugh L. Carey) Commission on the International Year of the Child in cooperation with the New York City Department of Parks and Recreation (Gordon J. Davis, Commissioner).
    - Westbeth 10th Anniversary Celebration poster, 1980 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster designed by R.P. Sullivan and printed by ConEdison. Westbeth is an artists' community in the West Village.
    - "Britain Salutes New York 1983" (Folder 09-07)
      The event was sponsored by the New York International Arts Festival and celebrated the 200th year anniversary of the signing of the Treaty of Paris. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: May 12 1983.
    - Third Annual Presidential Conference at Hofstra University Cultural Center, 1984 (Folder 09-07)
      The poster was designed by Francoise Gilot and features an image of Dwight D. Eisenhower, the Presidential Conference's focus that year. Alongside the large poster are two copies of a smaller poster featuring a photograph of Dwight D. Eisenhower, courtesy of Dwight D. Eisenhower Library. One copy is signed by "Susan Eisenhower", "Tex McCrary", and a third illegible signature. The other copy is stamped, "Approved for posting by the Office of Secretary". There is also 3 copied pages from the program booklet - the cover of the booklet and two pages, "About the Speakers". On the back of one copy of the small poster is the address of Susan Douglas.
    - Advertisement for the South Street Seaport Museum's Lamplight tour with the Ghost of Herman Melville, 1986 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster hand-set and printed at Bowne & Co., Stationers. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: Dec 17 1986.
    - Daily News and NYC Police Department Public Service Announcement for a safer New York, 1988 (Folder 09-07)
      The poster is designed by George Sargent and Frank Henry. The poster is directed at children with the main idea to beware of strangers.
    - "1989-1990 Freedom Spreads..." (Folder 09-07)
      Poster printed by Matthews Marketing, Inc. under exclusive licensing rights from New York Times, Agence France-Presse, Bettman Reuters and Associated Press. Poster features a mock-up of a New York Times front page with headlines and photographs concerning freedom and democracy.
    - 21st New York City Marathon poster, 1990 (Folder 09-07)
      2 copies. Photograph on poster is credited to Duomo/David Madison. 1990 sponsors included Manufacturers Hanover, Mercedes-Benz, John Hancock, ASICS, The Rudin Family, and Runner's World.
    - Ground Breaking Ceremony for Eleanor Roosevelt Monument, 1993 (Folder 09-07)
      The poster features a photograph of the monument and the ground breaking was sponsored by the Eleanor Roosevelt Monument Fund and took place at Riverside Park and 72nd Street.
    - Reward poster for arrest and conviction of person who framed O.J., 1994 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster features mug shot of O.J. Simpson and offers a $500,000 reward for arrest and conviction of person or persons who framed O.J. In pencil on front, "Original - American Life Post".
    - "Indian Point - Safe. Secure. Vital", c.2001 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster by AmericanCampaignStore.com. Poster is folded in half lengthwise and stapled. Presumably it was used as a yard sign.
    - The 25th Annual Mermaid Parade at Cony Island, 2007 (Folder 09-08)
      Poster designed by Marc Kehoe and printed by Coney Island U.S.A. Sponsors of the parade included the Cyclones, Keyspan, Brooklyn Brewery, Taconic Investment Management, Astroland Amusement Park.
    - Centennial Commemoration of the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory Fire by Workers United/SEIU (ILGWU), 2011 (Folder 09-07)
      Poster printed by Allied Printers 515.
    - Celebrating Brooklyn Basketball, 2013 (Folder 09-08)
      Poster is officially licensed by Black Fives, Inc. and designed by Soular Creative. The Barclays Center honors the legacy of African-American Basketball in Brooklyn with the celebration to benefit the Back Fives Foundation.
    - "Justice for LGBTQ People is Justice for All", 2019 (Folder 09-08)
      The poster is done by the New York City Anti-Violent Project and printed on both sides, one in English, one in Spanish. Note with poster states it is a gift of Linda Ferber in 2019.
    - "Trust TGNC People, We Know What We Need", 2019 (Folder 09-08)
      Poster is done by the New York City Anti-Violence Project and is printed on both sides, one in English, one in Spanish. A note with the poster states that it is a gift of Linda Ferber in 2019.
    - National Poetry Month April 2021, Celebrating 25 years (Folder 09-08)
      Artwork is by Bao Lu. Lines excerpted from the poem "For Keeps" by Joy Harjo.
  - Subseries IX.B. Protests (incl 1982 Disarmament Rally)
    - "Let's Fight Back" Citywide Action Group Against Neighborhood Destruction and For Low-Rent Housing, 1975 (Folder 09-14)
      Poster "hand silk screened by Publicity and Propaganda - HOMEFRONT". Poster in both English and Spanish. Accompanying note explains poster. "Landlords As Rats" by Mimi Rosenberg, courtesy of the artist and acquired for the exhibition "New York on the Brink".
    - Protest to Close Live Animal Labs at the American Museum of Natural History, 1976 (Folder 09-14)
      Poster features a photograph of Robert G. Goelet,a trustee and President of the American Museum of Natural History. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back, Jan 12 1977.
    - Disarmament Rally - "March for Peace & Justice. June 12, New York", 1982 (Folder 09-13)
      Poster desined by Seymour Chwast. Poster features dove superimposed on marching legs. Rally was to support The U.N. Special Session on Disarmament. On back, "Gift of Kathleen Hulser, 2004".
    - Disarmament Rally - "Save Life From Nuclear Disaster", 1982 (Folder 09-13)
      Sculpture featured in poster by Mary Frank; Photograph by Joel Meyerowitz. Poster sponsored by War Resisters League and includes the date of the Rally (June 12th) and also includes a day of Civil Disobedience (June 14th). On back, "Gift of Kathleen Hulser, 2004".
    - Disarmament Rally - "Rally Against The New Face of Nuclear War. Time To Make History Again.", 1982 (Folder 09-13)
      Peace Action of New York State was the lead sponsor for event (and poster) held at The Ethical Culture Society at 7:00 p.m. on June 12, 1982 after the Central Park Rally. Speakers and entertainers included: Jane Alexander, Ruby Dee & Ossie Davis, Cora Weiss, Grace Paley, Dennis Kucinich, David Cortright, Randall Fosberg, Jonathan Schell & Circus Amok. On back, "Gift of Kathleen Hulser, 2004".
    - Disarmament Rally - Keith Haring Anti-Nuke poster, 1982 (Folder 09-13)
      Poster created by Keith Haring in 1982. Poster features a "Radiant Baby". On back, "Gift of Keith Haring Foundation, 2002".
    - Disarmament Rally - "A transfer of military budgets to human needs. A freeze and reduction of nuclear weapons.", 1982 (Folder 09-13)
      2 copies. Poster created by Giancarlo Impiglia and sponsored by the June 12 Rally Committee. On backs of Copy 1 and Copy 2, "Gift of Kathleen Hulser, 2004".
    - Disarmament Rally - "First Angry Dove", 1982 (Folder 09-13)
      Below image, "A/P 8/10 First Angry Dove" and signed by artist, L(?).K.L(?). On back, "Gift of the artist".
    - Fair Share Tax Day Demonstration - "Deadbeat Dozen Tax Bill. J.P. Morgan Chase", 2011 (Folder 09-14)
      Poster "paid for MOVEON.ORG Political Action HTTP://POL.MOVEON.ORG not authorized by any candidate or candidate's committee." Gift of Kathleen Hulser, 2011.
    - Fair Share Tax Day Demonstration - "Deadbeat Dozen Tax Bill. Goldman Sachs", 2011 (Folder 09-14)
    - March for our Lives Demonstration - "Not One More", 2018 (Folder 09-14)
      Poster created by THOUGHTMATTER and a 2018 gift of THOUGHTMATTER. Poster features a gun with "Not one more".
    - March for our Lives Demonstration - "Enough", 2018 (Folder 09-14)
      The poster was created by THOUGHTMATTER and a 2018 gift of THOUGHTMATTER. Poster features an image of a hand in the shape of a gun and "Enough".
  - Subseries IX.C. Women Activism/Rights (incl 2017 Women's March)
    - "WAC (Women's Action Coalition) Is Watching...Women Take Action", ca. 1992 (Folder OSFF-09-32)
      Poster published by WAC and features the WAC blue dot logo superimposed over an eye.
    - Fierce Pussy, 2008 (Folder OSFF-09-32)
      Poster designed by Fierce Pussy and published by Printed Matter, Inc. Poster printed for gallery show held in April/May of 2008 in New York City.
    - Women's March - "Rights Take Might", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
      Poster designed by THOUGHTMATTER.
    - Women's March - "This Pussy Grabs Back", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - Women's March - "This Pussy Grabs Back", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
      Poster designed by THOUGHTMATTER. Poster features the image of a cat's head.
    - Women's March - "Keep Your Rosaries Off My Ovaries", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - Women's March - "Representation Not Exploitation", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - Women's March - "Silence Equals Violence", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - Women's March - "Silence Equals Violence", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
      Poster designed by THOUGHTMATTER. Poster features image of head of Statue of Liberty with mouth bound by barbed wire.
    - Women's March - "Get Your Laws Off My Body", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - Women's March - "Left or Right. We Can All See Wrong", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - Women's March - "We Will Not Be Silenced", 2017 (Folder 09-15)
    - "Nasty Women Are Watching", ca. 2019 (Folder OSFF-09-32)
      Poster by artist, Elizabeth Langer. 2 copies, slight variation. One copy's central image is of a female figure; the other copy's central image is of a face mask.
    - "Right to Choose", 2021 (Folder OSFF-09-32)
      Poster by artists, Carmen Winant and Laia Abril. Features image of coat hanger on one side and obituaries of feminist leaders on the other side.
  - Subseries IX.D. 200th Anniversary of Washington Inauguration
    - Milton Glaser poster for 200th Anniversary of Washington's Inauguration, 1989 (Folder 09-22)
      2 copies (1 signed by Milton Glaser). Logo designed by Chermayeff & Geismar Associates; poster designed by Milton Glaser. Poster features a profile of George Washington outlined with fireworks. Attached letter from the New York City Commission on the Bicentennial of the Constitution about the donation.
    - "Washington Landing at the foot of Wall Street" Anniversary poster, 1989 (Folder 09-22)
      Reprint of image by Ernest Peixotto from the Marine Art Collection of The Seaman's Bank for Savings, FSB. Attached letter from the New York City Commission on the Bicentennial of the Constitution about donation.
    - "After 200 Years, This is Still the Biggest Gamble Ever to Take Place on Wall Street" Anniversary advertisement, 1989 (Folder 09-22)
      Advertisement for the Inauguration celebration activities by Lowe Marschalk, Inc. "Copy:H.Karp, Art:S.Ohman, Acct:A.Smith, Traffic:E.Laurido, Production:R.DelVecchio". Poster features image of Washington's Inauguration courtesy of the Mount Vernon Ladies' Association. Poster also lists the sponsors and patrons of the events.
    - Advertisement listing events, exhibits, and programs of the 200th Anniversary of Washington's Inauguration, 1989 (Folder 09-22)
      Advertisement for the Inauguration celebration activities by Lowe Marschalk, Inc. "Copy:H.Karp, Art:S.Ohman, Acct:A.Smith, Traffic:E.Laurido, Production:R.DelVecchio". "This advertisement paid for by The Henley Group, Inc. and Wheelabrator Technologies, Inc." The images are primarily from the Bettmann Archive; one is from Historical Pictures Service, Chicago. The poster also lists the sponsors and patrons of the events.
  - Subseries IX.E. War/Vietnam
    - Advertisement for Evening to hear Reports on the Crisis Conference of the National Committee for Peaceful Alternatives held in Washington, D.C., 1951 (Folder 09-16)
      The evening was sponsored by The Metropolitan Council for Peaceful Alternatives and The Greenwich Village Council for Peaceful Alternatives. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back, Nov 7 1951.
    - Fifth Avenue Vietnam Peace Parade and Rally - "Stop The War In Vietnam Now!", 1966 (Folder 09-16)
      2 copies. Speakers included: Linus Pauling, Fannie Lou Hamer, Donald Duncan, and Juan Mari Bras. Rally was sponsored by Fifth Avenue Vietnam Peace Parade Committee, A.J. Muste, chairman.
    - Call for Entries for International Poster Competition on theme: "No More War", 1967 (Folder 09-16)
      The poster was created by and the competition was sponsored by Avant Garde with the winning posters to be featured in Avant Garde Magazine. The poster was printed in the U.S.A.
    - "Why Are We Burning, Torturing, Killing The People of Vietnam?", c. 1967 (Folder OSFF-09-30)
      Poster designed by Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) of New York. Poster features image of a young vietnamese girl burned by napalm. Urges people to protest war by writing to President Johnson and learning the facts by writing to SDS.
    - "Stop The War In Vietnam Now!", c. 1968 (Folder 09-16)
      Poster features a photograph of an injured soldier being carried.
    - Vietnamese woman carrying two children with soldier behind her poster., c. 1968 (Folder 09-16)
      The poster is simply the photograph of the woman carrying the two children without any words.
  - Subseries IX.F. Medical/Health (incl AIDS)
    - Christmas Seals 1936 Holiday Greetings (Folder 09-09)
      Message was to protect your home from Tuberculosis. On back is an easel stand.
    - Red Cross Christmas Roll Call advertisement, 1938 (Folder 09-09)
      On back, in pencil, "EB Child Feb. 1946". Also on back, "1938. Giving [unreadable] Danes Hall. E.C."
    - "Special Exhibition 'For Humanity's Sake' From Sanitary Commission to [Red Cross]", 1942 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster made by NYC WPA War Services. Special exhibition was held at the Museum of the City of New York. Acquisition date (?) on back: Dec. 28, 1942.
    - "Game Week to Fight Infantile Paralysis", 1942 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster designed by Garrett Price and printed by L.U. 230. Asks that whenever you play collect a kitty to go to Women's Division Greater New York Committee or send checks to the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis. In back, in pencil, "Copy 1. Apr. 27, 1942."
    - "no home remedy ever cured GONORRHEA", 1943 (Folder 09-10)
      Poster designed by Fellnagel (Dorothy Darling) for the United States Public Health Service - VD15. Acquisition date (?) on front, Jan.2, 1943.
    - United States Public Health Service Syphilis Poster, 1943 (Folder 09-10)
      Poster designed by Karsakov (Leonard) for the United States Public Health Service - 12. Focus of poster is health of babies born to treated/untreated mothers with Syphilis. Acquisition date (?) on front, Jan. 2, 1943.
    - "NO home remedy or quack ever cured syphilis or gonorrhea see your doctor or health officer", 1943 (Folder 09-10)
      Poster designed by Karsakov (Leonard) for the United States Public Health Service - VD7-R41. Acquisition date (?) on front, Jan. 2, 1943.
    - "A Blood Test for EVERYONE The Only Sure Check - Syphilis...", 1943 (Folder 09-10)
      Poster designed by Fellnagel (Dorothy Darling) for the United States Public Health Service. Acquisition date (?) on front, Jan. 2, 1943.
    - U.S. Navy Bureau of Medicine and Surgery "The Elephant is thick-skinned - but he never FORGETS!", 1944 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster designed by Bode and printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office in cooperation with the U.S. Naval Medical School, National Naval Medical Center, Bethesda, MD.
    - Johnson & Johnson First Aid Instruction, 1946 (Folder 09-10)
      Poster printed in U.S.A. Includes several illustrations and instructions for many emergencies. Acquisition date (?) on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
    - "Don't Strip Tease for Anopheles" Malaria poster, 1946 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster printed by the U.S. Government Printing Office. Note at bottom explains July 46 distribution of the "Don't Strip Tease for Anopheles": "Distribution: Continental: Special distribution. Overseas to Pacific and Caribbean Areas only:..." Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: May 11 1950.
    - "Aedes Mosquitoes Bite Night And Day" Dengue Fever poster, 1946 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster printed by U.S. Government Printing Office. Note at bottom explains "Dengue Fever" distribution in July 1946: "Distribution: Continental: Special distribution. Overseas to Pacific and Caribbean Areas only:..." Acquisition date (?) stamped on back: May 11 1950.
    - "GIVE!" Red Cross self-easel, 1947 (Folder 09-09)
      "Litho in U.S.A." Includes instructions on creating self-easel. Acquisition date (?) on back, Mar. 21, 1947.
    - "Blood Saves Lives. Make a Date to Save a Life.", 1948 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster designed by Jes Wilhelm Schlaikjer and printed by L.I.P. & B.A., New York on behalf of The American National Red Cross, Poster 1401. In white box on front: "April 18, 1956" and acquisition date (?) stamped on back: Apr. 18 1956.
    - Red Cross "Give" Main Street poster, 1948 (Folder 09-09)
      Poster designed by Steven Dohanos and printed by L.I.P. & B.A., New York. Acquisition date (?) on back: Feb. 5, 1948.
    - New York Regional Blood Bank Program, 1956 (Folder 09-09)